American Psychosomatic Society Records Finding Aid
Oskar Diethelm Library
- Psychosomatic Medicine Journal
  - Manuscript Reviews and Correspondence, 1939 - 1991; The Published and Rejected Manuscripts series are arranged alphabetically by author's last name. The Accepted and Rejected Manuscripts series is arranged chronologically. All three series contain correspondence between editors and authors documenting the acceptance and rejection processes employed by the Journal for selecting manuscripts for publication in the Journal. Editors' reviews or critiques are available for many of the manuscripts accepted or rejected for publication. Additional critiques and reviews reflective of the manuscript review process before it was formalized in the early to mid 1940s are found within the text of editors' correspondence with one another in the Editors subgroup of Record Group 1. The Accepted and Rejected series contains correspondence about accepted and rejected manuscripts (1985-1991). These more recent files contain fewer documents than their predecessors and due to budget constraints, have not been placed in acid-free folders. Files with red labels indicate files for manuscripts rejected for publication; green labels indicate acceptance. NOTE: The three series above do not include the manuscripts themselves, which were returned to their authors by the Society. To note the location of the few manuscripts which were discovered, a letter "A" for abstract or "M" for manuscript has been printed on the top righthand corner of the relevant folders.
    - Published Manuscripts, 1939 - 1984
      - Aa-Ab, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Ac-Ada, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Ade-Adz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Ae-Al, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Am-Ap M, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 22, Box 23)
      - Aq-Az, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Bar-Baz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Bea-Bee, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Ba-Baq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 23, Box 24)
      - Bef-Ben, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Beo-Bez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Bi-Bla, 1939 - 1984 (Box 24)
      - Ble-Blz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Bo, 1939 - 1984 (Box 25)
      - Bra-Bri, 1939 - 1984 (Box 25)
      - Bro, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 25)
      - Bru-Bz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 25)
      - Ca, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Ce-Ci, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 26)
      - Cl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Coa-Cog, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Coh, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 26, Box 27)
      - Coi-Coz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Cr-Cz, 1939 - 1984 (Box 27)
      - Daa-Dat, 1939 - 1984 (Box 27)
      - Dau-Daz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - De, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Dia-Dim, 1939 - 1984 (Box 28)
      - Din-Do, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Dr-Dz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Ea-Em, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Ena-Engel, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Ep-Ez, 1939 - 1984 (Box 28)
      - Fa, 1939 - 1984 (Box 29)
      - Fe, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Fh-Fi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Fl-Forr, 1939 - 1984 (Box 29)
      - Fors-Foz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Fra-Fre, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Friedman, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 30)
      - Fro-Fz, 1939 - 1984 (Box 30)
      - Ga-Ge, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Gi-Gn, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Goa-Goo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 30, Box 31)
      - Gop-Goz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Gra, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Gre, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Gri, 1939 - 1984 (Box 31)
      - Gro-Gz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Haa-Ham, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Han-Haz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Hea-Hel, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Hem-Hez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Hi-Hoe, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Hof M, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Hog-Hos, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Hot-Hz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - I, 1939 - 1984 (Box 33)
      - Ja, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 34)
      - Jea-Jez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Ji-Jz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Ka-Kao, 1939 - 1984 (Box 34)
      - Kap-Kaz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Kar-Kat, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Kau-Kel, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Kem-Kez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Kia-Kin, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Kio-Kl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Kn, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Ko, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Kr-Kz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 36)
      - La-Lah, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Lai-Laz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Lea-Leu, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Lev-Lez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Lh-Lie, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Lif-Liz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Ll-Lo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 37)
      - Lub, 1939 - 1984 (Box 38)
      - Luc-Lz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Ma-Mak, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Mal-Man, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Mao-Mas, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Mass-Mat, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Mca-Mcd, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Mce-Mcz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Me-Mel, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Mem-Mez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Mi, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 40)
      - Moa-Moq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 40)
      - Mor-Mz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 40)
      - Na, 1939 - 1984 (Box 40)
      - Ne-Nz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 40)
      - O, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 41)
      - Pa-Par, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Pas-Paz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Pe-Peq, 1939 - 1984 (Box 41)
      - Per-Pez, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 41)
      - Pf-Pi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Pl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Po-Q, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Raa-Rah, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Rai-Raz, 1939 - 1984 (Box 42)
      - Rea-Red, 1939 - 1984 (Box 42)
      - Ree-Rei, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 43)
      - Ref-Rez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 43)
      - Ri, 1939 - 1984 (Box 43)
      - Rob-Rod, 1939 - 1984 (Box 43)
      - Rof-Rom, 1939 - 1984 (Box 43)
      - Ros, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 43)
      - Rot, 1939 - 1984 (Box 43)
      - Ru, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 44)
      - Sab-Sai, 1939 - 1984 (Box 44)
      - San-Sas, 1939 - 1984 (Box 44)
      - Sas-Sau, 1939 - 1984 (Box 44)
      - Sca, 1939 - 1984 (Box 44)
      - Sche, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 44)
      - Schi-Schm, 1939 - 1984 (Box 44)
      - Schn, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Scho-Schr, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Schw-Sco, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Seg-Sei, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Sei-Sew, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Sha, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - She-Shr, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Sia-Sil, 1939 - 1984 (Box 45)
      - Sk-Sm, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 46)
      - Sl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Sn-So, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Sp-Sq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Sta, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Stein, 1939 - 1984 (Box 47)
      - Stej-Stez, 1939 - 1984 (Box 47)
      - Sti-Str, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Stu, 1939 - 1984 (Box 47)
      - Su-Sz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 47, Box 48)
      - Ta-Te, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Th-Tz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 48)
      - U-Va, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Ve-Vz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Wa-Wal, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Wam-Waz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Wea-Wein, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Weir-Weiz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Wej-Wez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Wh-Wik, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 49, Box 50)
      - Wil-Will, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 50)
      - Wilm-Wol, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 50)
      - Wom-Woz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 50)
      - X-Z, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 50)
    - Rejected Manuscripts, 1939 - 1984
      - Aa-Ab, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 51)
      - Ac-Alek, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 51)
      - Alem-Alz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Am-Aq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Ar, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 51)
      - As-Az, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Ba-Bard, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 52)
      - Bare-Baz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 52)
      - Bea-Bec, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Bed-Beq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Bera-Berg, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Berh-Bez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Bf-Bi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Bla-Ble, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Bli-Blon, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Blo-Bly, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Bm-Bo, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 54)
      - Bra-Bri, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Broa-A.Brown, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - B.Brown-Broz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Bru-Buc, 1939 - 1984 (Box 54)
      - Bud-Bz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Ca-Cal, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Cam-Caq, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Car-Caz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Ce-Cher, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 55)
      - Ches-Chz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Ci-Cla, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Cle-Clz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Coa-Coh, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 56)
      - Col-Coo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Cop-Cow, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Cox-Cz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 57)
      - Da-Dd, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Dea-Dem, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 57)
      - Den-Der, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Des-Dez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Di-Dor, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Dos-Drus, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Drut-Dz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Ea-Ed, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Ef-Ei, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Ej-Em, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 59)
      - En-Eo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 59)
      - Ep-Ez, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 59)
      - Fa-Fel, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 59)
      - Fem-Fie, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 59)
      - Fief-Fir, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Fis, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Fit-Fl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Foltz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Fo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Fra-Fre, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 60)
      - Fried, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Frief-Fz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Ga-Gan, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Gao-Gaz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 61)
      - Gea-Gen, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Geo-Gez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Gh-Gi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Gl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Gm-Goo, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 62)
      - Gop-Goz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Gra, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Grea-Greenb, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Greene-Grez M, 1939 - 1984 (Box 63)
      - Gri-Grz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 63)
      - G from Gu M, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Ha-Hal, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Ham-Han, 1939 - 1984 (Box 63)
      - Hap-Harr, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hart-Haz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hea-Hek, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hel, 1939 - 1984 (Box 64)
      - Hem-Hez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hoa-Hok, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Hol-Holm, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Holn-Hor, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Hos-Hz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 65)
      - I, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Ja-Jam, 1939 - 1984 (Box 65)
      - Jan-Jn, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Jo-Jz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Ka-Kan, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Kao-Kar, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Kas-Kaz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 66)
      - Kea-Kel, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Kem-Ken, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 67)
      - Kep-Kez, 1939 - 1984 (Box 67)
      - Kh-Kj, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 67)
      - Kl-Kn, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 67)
      - Koa-Kolm, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 67)
      - Koln-Koz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 67)
      - Kra-Kro, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 68)
      - Kru-Kz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 68)
      - La, 1939 - 1984; 4 folders (Box 68)
      - Lea-Lee, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 68)
      - Lef-Leo, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 68)
      - Lep-Leu, 1939 - 1984 (Box 69)
      - Lev, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 69)
      - Lew-Lez, 1939 - 1984 (Box 69)
      - Lia-Lin, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 69)
      - Lio-Ll, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 69)
      - Loa-Lot, 1939 - 1984 (Box 69)
      - Lou-Loz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 69)
      - Lua-Lud, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Lue-Lz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Maa-Mak, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Mal, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Mam-Man, 1939 - 1984 (Box 70)
      - Mao-Mark, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Marl- Mas, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 70)
      - Mat-Maz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 71)
      - Mca-Mcc, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 71)
      - Mcf-Mcz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Mc-Mee, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 71)
      - Mef-Mem, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Men, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Meo-Mez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Mia-Milk, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Miller, 1939 - 1984 (Box 72)
      - Milles-Miz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Moa-Mon, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 73)
      - Moo, 1939 - 1984 (Box 73)
      - Mop-Moz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 73)
      - Mp-Mz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 73)
      - Na, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 74)
      - Nea-Nez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Nia-Nz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Oa-Om, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - On-Oz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Pa-Paq, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 75)
      - Par, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 75)
      - Pas-Paz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 75)
      - Pea-Perr, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 75)
      - Pers-Ph, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 75)
      - Pi, 1939 - 1984; 4 folders (Box 76)
      - Pl, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 76)
      - Po, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 76)
      - Pr-Pu, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 76)
      - Q, 1939 - 1984 (Box 77)
      - Ra-Raj, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 77)
      - Rak-Raz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 77)
      - Rea-Reg, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 77)
      - Reh-Rez, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 77)
      - Rh-Ri, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 78)
      - Rh-Roe, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Rof-Rosa, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Rose-Rosenb M, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Rosenc-Rosz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Rot, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Rou-Rz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 79)
      - Sa-Sal, 1939 - 1984 (Box 80)
      - Sam-Saz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Sb-Sche, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Schi-Schn, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 80)
      - Scho-Schu, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Schw-Scho, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Sea-Sei, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Sej-Sez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Sha, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Shc-Shz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 81)
      - Sia-Sik, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Sil, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Sim-Siz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Sk-G.Smith, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - H.Smith-Smy, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Sn-So, 1939 - 1984; 4 folders (Box 82, Box 83)
      - Spa-Spn, 1939 - 1984 (Box 83)
      - Spn-Spz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 83)
      - Sta-Steh, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 83)
      - Stei-Step, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 83)
      - Ster-Stez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 83)
      - Sti-Stz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 84)
      - Su, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Sv-Sz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Ta, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Te, 1939 - 1984 (Box 84)
      - Tf-Tk, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 84)
      - To, 1939 - 1984 (Box 85)
      - Tr-Tz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 85)
      - U, 1939 - 1984 (Box 85)
      - Va, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Ve-Vi, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Vl-Vz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Waa-Wak, 1939 - 1984 (Box 86)
      - Wal-Waz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Wea-Weir, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Weiss-Wez, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Wej-Wh, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Wia-Wilk, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Will-Wilz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Wim-Wiz, 1939 - 1984; 3 folders (Box 87)
      - Wj-Wood, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 87)
      - Wol-Wz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 87)
      - X-Y, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 87)
      - Za-Zag, 1939 - 1984 (Box 87)
      - Zh-Zz, 1939 - 1984; 2 folders (Box 87)
    - Accepted and Rejected Manuscripts, 1985 - 1991
      - 1985-1986 (Box 88)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 89)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 90)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 91)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 92)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 93)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 94)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 95)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 96)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 97)
      - 1989 (Box 98)
      - 1989 (Box 99)
      - 1989 (Box 100)
      - 1989 (Box 101)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 102)
      - 1990 (Box 103)
      - 1990 (Box 104)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 105)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 106)
  - Monograph Reviews and Correspondence, 1938 - 1964; Organized by author's last name. Through Paul B. Hoeber, Inc., the medical division of Harper and Brothers, the Society intermittently published several monographs from 1939 on. A Harvard University related monograph series taken over by the Journal while under the sponsorship of the National Research Council ended in 1942, however, some irregular publication of monographs continued for several years. The Published Monograph series contains telegrams, publisher's invoices, correspondence among printers, publishers, authors and editors, and copyright registration forms. The Rejected Monographs series contains correspondence and some reviews. An example of files found in this series includes three folders of requests for copies of Benedek and Rubinstein's monograph, "Sexual Cycles in Women" (1940-1943). NOTE: These series do not contain drafts, reviews, or copies of the monographs themselves.
    - Published Monographs, 1939 - 1961
      - Alexander "Psychogenic Factors in Bronchial Asthma", 1941 - 1943; 2 folders (Box 107)
      - Anderson "Experimental Neuroses in the Sheep and Dog", 1941 - 1942 (Box 107)
      - Benedek and Rubenstein "Sexual Cycles in Women", 1940 - 1943; 3 folders (Box 107)
      - Binger "Personality in Arterial Hypertension", 1945 - 1947; 3 folders (Box 107)
      - Bliss and Harden Branch "Anorexia Nervosa", 1956 - 1960 (Box 107)
      - Cobb and White "Mucus Colitis", 1939 - 1946; 2 folders (Box 107)
      - Derner "Certain Aspects of the Tuberculose", 1951 - 1952 (Box 107)
      - Gantt "Origin and Development of Behavior", 1943; 3 folders (Box 107)
      - Kardiner "The Traumatic Neurosis of War", 1940 - 1943; 4 folders (Box 108)
      - Klein, Potter and Dyk "Pregnancy and Childbirth – A Psychiatric Study", 1948 - 1950 (Box 108)
      - Masserman "Behavior and Neurosis", 1942 - 1943 (Box 108)
      - Newton "Attitudes of Mothers of Newborn Babies Toward their Biological Feminine Function", 1952 - 1955 (Box 108)
      - Ruesch "Chronic Disease in Psychological Invalidism", 1945 - 1951; 4 folders (Box 108)
      - Wenar "The Mother - Child Interaction in Psychosomatic Disorders and Severe Emotional Disturbances", 1960 - 1961 (Box 108)
      - Wittkower and Russell "Emotional Factors in Skin Disease", 1952 (Box 108)
    - Rejected Monographs, 1938 - 1964
      - Aschner "Philosophy of Modern Medicine", 1942 (Box 109)
      - Bhandari "The Personality Background in Pulmonary Tuberculosis", 1953 (Box 109)
      - Brown "Current Conceptions of Impotence and Frigidity", 1954 (Box 109)
      - Brozek "Diet and Behavior", 1960 - 1961 (Box 109)
      - Coghill "Early Embryonic Somatic Movements in Birds and Mammals other than Man", 1938 - 1939 (Box 109)
      - Curtis and Faterson "Psychosomatic Aspects of Pernicious Anemia", 1956 - 1957 (Box 109)
      - Goldberg "Family Influence in Psychosomatic Illness", 1955 - 1958; 2 folders (Box 109)
      - Kasanin "Language and Thought in Schizophrenia", 1941 (Box 109)
      - Lakin "An Investigation of Personality Characteristics of Mothers of Excessively Crying Infants", 1955 (Box 109)
      - Loewy "Vegetative Stigmatisation", 1942 (Box 109)
      - Patterson "Experimental and Comparative Studies in Psychophysiology", 1941 (Box 109)
      - Poser "Personality Tests in Psychosomatic Research", 1954 (Box 109)
      - Rapaport "The Influence of Emotions on Memories", 1941 (Box 109)
      - Rosenman "Preface to a Theory of Disease Assessment", 1956 - 1957 (Box 109)
      - Royce "A Factorial Study of Emotionality in the Dog", 1952 - 1954 (Box 109)
      - Saul "Bibliography of Hostility", 1958 - 1961 (Box 109)
      - Schachter "A Psychophysiological Study of Pain, Fear, and Anger in Hypertensives and Normotensives", 1955 (Box 109)
      - Shands and Finesinger "Psychiatric Aspects of Fatigue", 1949 - 1950 (Box 109)
      - Sifneos "Descent into Chaos. A Psychosomatic Case Study", 1961 - 1964 (Box 109)
      - Spitz "Infantile Neuro-dermatitis", 1951 (Box 109)
      - Vernier (editor) "Cooperative Psychological Research in Tuberculosis", 1959 - 1960 (Box 109)
      - Wenar "A Psychosomatic Ward for Children", 1957 - 1958 (Box 109)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 109)
- Annual Meetings
  - Administrative Files, 1943 - 1987; Organized chronologically and by meeting location. The Society held one conference annually, most often in Atlantic City, New Jersey. For early meetings only (1943-1947), files include transcripts of conference proceedings which contain business meeting reports as well as scholarly panel discussions. Some of these proceedings are fragile and have sustained water damage. The bulk of the records in the Administrative Files document administrative planning arrangements by the Program Committee for annual meetings. Topics covered include hotel arrangements and specific session or panel topics and speakers. Files include financial records, Program Committee minutes, and correspondence about manuscripts accepted or rejected for presentation at annual meetings. A few manuscripts and abstracts are located in folders marked "M" (for manuscripts) or "A" (for abstracts) in their righthand corners. The administrative files show how meeting terminology changed over time, as "speakers," for example, later became "discussants." The term "brief communications" was used to signify presentations delivered that were shorter than papers.
    - Detroit 1943 Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 110)
    - Chicago 1944 Conference Proceedings (Box 110)